{"tossups": [{"question": "In one episode in this TV show, a character tells a story about his mother, sister, and some female scorpions to pass the Bechdel test. A character in this show sells a gun to the assassin Krombopulos Michael to get money for video games. During one episode in this show, a character escapes from a Russian prison with the help of Jaguar before going to see (*) Dr. Wong. In the premiere of this show's third season, a character claims \"Nine more seasons until I get that Szechuan sauce\" during a nonsensical rant. In one episode of this season, a character turns himself into a pickle to avoid going to therapy with his daughter Beth. For 10 points, name this Adult Swim TV show featuring the title mad scientist and his grandson.", "answer": "Rick and Morty", "subcategory": "Trash", "category": "Trash"}, {"question": "Two of these objects swap positions every four years in an example of a co-orbital system. One of these objects is the most reflective body in the solar system with an albedo of 1.38. Another one of these objects maintains the Encke gap by \"shepherding.\" The unexpected increase in tidal heating on one of these objects results in \"tiger stripes,\" which are centers for (*) cryovolcanism. The only known satellite with a dense atmosphere is one of these objects, and the Huygens probe landed on that object in 2006. Examples of these objects include Minas, Tethys, and Titan. For 10 points, name these objects that orbit the 6th planet from the Sun which has an extensive ring system.", "answer": "Saturn's moons [or moons of Saturn; prompt on moons by asking \"of which planet?\"]", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "The location of this empire's capital was decided after a priest planted two kum trees and picked the one that grew more. One ruler of this kingdom killed Charles McCarthy and used his skull as a drinking cup. This kingdom's ruler Bonsu allied with the Netherlands in a war against the Fante Confederacy. This empire won the battle of Feyiase against the Denkyira kingdom. Queen Yaa (*) Asantewaa of this empire started a war after Frederick Hodgson demanded that he sit on a certain sacred object. Osei Tutu founded this empire. Great Britain fought the War of the Golden Stool against this empire. For 10 points, name this African empire centered in modern-day Ghana.", "answer": "Ashanti Empire [or Asante Empire]", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "One of this artist's paintings depicts a group of five young women taunting five young men, all of which are mostly or entirely nude. This artist painted multiple scenes of pit orchestras, including one set At the Opera. While visiting his uncle, this artist painted a scene in which a group of men inspect the title good while this painter's brother reads a newspaper about the collapse of his business. A woman at the Caf\u00e9 de la Nouvelle Ath\u00e8nes stares forward dejectedly over a (*) glass of the title beverage in another painting by this artist  This artist stepped outside of his primary medium when he created a wax sculpture depicting a young girl standing in fourth position. For 10 points, name this Impressionist who painted A Cotton Office in New Orleans and frequently created scenes of ballerinas, including Little Dancer of Fourteen Years.", "answer": "Edgar Degas", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "In one story by this author, a girl calls Ruby Turpin an \"old wart hog\" after throwing a book at her. This author of \"Revelation\" wrote about a character who wears a green hat which \"looked like a cushion with the stuffing out\" and has a velvet flap. One character created by this author states that Jesus had \"thrown everything off balance\" before claiming that the protagonist would have been good \"if it had been somebody there to (*) shoot her every minute of her life.\" Julian's mother dies at a bus stop after being assaulted by another woman in a story by this author. This author of \"Everything That Rises Must Converge\" wrote a story in which \"The Grandmother\" is murdered by The Misfit. For 10 points, name this American author of Southern Gothic stories like \"A Good Man Is Hard to Find.\"", "answer": "Flannery O'Connor", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This element is used as a catalyst in a reaction that couples two acetones to form pinacol. Compounds that contain this element are applied to dry ice to form carboxylic acids. Compounds containing this metal attack carbonyls to form alcohols and are commonly used to form new carbon-carbon bonds. This metal reduces titanium tetrachloride in the Kroll process. This element is bonded to a halogen and an alkyl group in (*) Grignard reagents. This element is coordinated to four nitrogen atoms in the porphyrin ring of chlorophyll. This element's sulfate, which is often used in agriculture and foot baths, is called Epsom salt. For 10 points, name this alkaline earth metal with atomic number 12 and symbol Mg.", "answer": "magnesium [or Mg before mentioned]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "This character enters a city under the pseudonym Philebus with \"The Tutor\" and meets a god disguised as Demetrios. This character believes himself to be the snake in his mother's dream where a snake bit her breast and blood curdled her milk. This character is first discovered by another after leaving a lock of his hair on his father's grave, along with a set of footprints. (*) Athena casts the tie breaking vote in favor of this character during a trial, saving him from the wrath of the Furies. This character schemes with his sister Electra to kill his mother Clytemnestra for killing his father Agamemnon. For 10 points, name this character who is the namesake of an Aeschylus trilogy.", "answer": "Orestes [accept Oresteia] [the first play is The Flies by Jean-Paul Sartre]", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This country includes very loud waves at Boka Pistol in part of its Shete Boka national park. That part of this country uses the peels of the lahara orange to produce a namesake blue liqueur. Maho Beach in this country is a popular place to spot planes landing on the runway of Princess Juliana International Airport, which also features flights to this country's island of Saba. The Arawakan language is believed to have influenced the (*) Papiamento creole currently spoken in constituent countries of this country. This country shares with France the island of Saint Martin and also controls the ABC islands that formed its namesake Antilles until 2010. For 10 points, name this European country which contains the islands of Curacao and Aruba in addition to its capital, Amsterdam.", "answer": "The Netherlands [or Holland; prompt on Cura\u00e7ao, Sint Maarten, Saint Martin, Aruba, or Bonaire]", "subcategory": "Geography", "category": "Geography"}, {"question": "One ruler of this non-Byzantine region named Robert was described as \"in mind most cunning\" by Anna Komnene. The conquest of this region began under Tancred of Hauteville and his sons. Gelon, the king of one city in this region, defeated a Carthiginian force at the Battle of Himera. The First Punic War started when a group of mercenaries from this region, the (*) Mamertines, allied with Rome. Alcibiades led a disastrous expedition to capture this region. While defending one city in this region, Archimedes used a giant mirror to burn Roman ships. Charles of Anjou lost control over this region in an 1282 Easter rebellion in its namesake \"Vespers.\" For 10 points, name this island with capital at Palmero, a triangular island located off the coast of Italy.", "answer": "Sicily [prompt on Italy] [the first clue refers to Robert Guiscard]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This opera's aria \"Il capro e la capretta\" claims wild animals get along better than men and women do. To begin this opera, two characters sing the duet \"Cinque, dieci, venti,\" about a bed's dimensions. That character from this opera sings an aria describing a profession with \"plenty of honor, little pay.\" This opera's aria \"L'ho perduta\" describes a pin being dropped, while another aria, \"Non Piu Andrai,\" mocks (*) Cherubino's assignment to the military. In this opera, Marcellina and Bartolo sue a man who they later realize is their son. In the final act of this opera, the Countess swaps clothes with Barbarina to embarrass Count Almaviva, the employer of the title character. For 10 points, name this opera by Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, the sequel to The Barber of Seville.", "answer": "The Marriage of Figaro", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This is the alphabetically first of two people who used media coverage of the Bulgarian connection to prove that the press manipulates public opinion. Another work by this man discusses an entity that has \"merge\" and \"move\" as its two main operations. This person developed bare phrase structure as part of his minimalist program. This man criticized B. F. Skinner's Verbal Behavior by arguing that some children suffer from a (*) \"poverty of the stimulus.\" This person developed x-bar theory, which was adopted into generative grammar. This man created the grammatically correct but meaningless sentence \"colorless green ideas sleep furiously.\" For 10 points, name this linguist who wrote Syntactic Structures and recently left MIT.", "answer": "Noam Chomsky", "subcategory": "Social Science", "category": "Social Science"}, {"question": "After one of these non-French events, Edwin Holland described one group as \"Jacobins of the country.\" The organizer of one of these events was a \"class leader\" who called a group of people the \"New Israelites.\" One of these events was possibly influenced by the passage of the Security Act of 1739. The actions of George Wilson and Joe LaRoche led to the failure of one of these events planned for Bastille Day. A man sometimes known as (*) Cato led the largest one of these events before the American Revolution, but he is often referred to as Jemmy. Denmark Vesey attempted one of these events, while another one took place near the Stono River. One of these insurrections was led by Nat Turner. For 10 points, name these insurrections against white plantation owners.", "answer": "slave revolts [accept slave rebellions or any other reasonable equivalents; prompt on revolts or rebellions or insurrections]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "A system where this scientist's laws are violated may lead to the external field effect, where a subsystem's dynamics are not affected by the surrounding system. This scientist names an interference pattern when light reflects between a flat and spherical surface. This scientist names a telescope that has a primary concave mirror and a secondary flat diagonal mirror. The rate of (*) heat transfer of an object is proportional to the temperature difference with its surroundings in this scientist's law of cooling. This scientist was the first to use a prism to split a beam of white light into its constituent colors. This scientist names the SI unit of force. For 10 points, name this scientist who names three laws of motion.", "answer": "Sir Isaac Newton [accept Modified Newtonian Dynamics; accept Newton's rings; accept Newtonian telescope]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "One of these figures created the other figures when he took off his garments and jewelry to bathe. One of these figures turns into sea foam after getting his hand caught in a shell when fishing, and originally guarded one end of the bridge that connects heaven and earth. Another one of these figures owns a jewel that can control tides. In some versions of The Record of Ancient Matters, the names of these figures have lofty titles such as (*) \"His-Swift-Impetuous-Male-Augustness.\" Two of these figures used a jewel encrusted spear to stir the ocean. One of these figures hid in the Heavenly Cave to escape her brother. These figures include Susano'o and Izanagi. For 10 points, name these figures who are worshiped in Shintoism.", "answer": "Kami [prompt on Shinto gods or equivalents]", "subcategory": "Mythology", "category": "Mythology"}, {"question": "This poet wrote a poem where a salesperson tries to sell a man a wife who will \"bring teacups\" and \"do whatever you tell it\" that concludes stating \"Will you marry it, marry it, marry it.\" In addition to \"The Applicant,\" the speaker of one of this poets' poems describes worms as \"sticky pearls\" and herself as \"a smiling woman\" before comparing herself to a cat who has \"nine times to die.\" That poem remarks that (*) \"Dying / Is an art\" and ends with the speaker warning \"I eat men like air.\" The title character of another one of this poet's poems has \"a cleft in [his] chin instead of [his] foot\" and \"a Meinkampf look\" and is called a \"bastard\" by the speaker, who declares \"I'm through.\" For 10 points, name this Confessionalist poet of \"Lady Lazarus\" and \"Daddy.\"", "answer": "Sylvia Plath", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "A mutation in the ABCA12 gene causes the \"harlequin\" type of a disease affecting this organ in infants. A type of surgery that began as chemosurgery is used to treat this organ and was developed by Frederic Mohs. Benzoyl peroxide is used to treat conditions of this organ. PPD is injected into this organ in the (*) Mantoux test for tuberculosis. Pacinian corpuscles are mechanoreceptors in this organ. This organ includes the stratum corneum and stratum lucidum. Diseases that affect this organ include vitiligo and psoriasis. Ultraviolet radiation increases the risk of melanoma in this organ. For 10 points, name this largest organ in the human body that is covered by the epidermis.", "answer": "skin", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "One of this author's novels includes a poem that repeats \"Are you not weary of ardent ways?\" The first sentence of one book by this author, which mentions a \"commodius vicus of recirculation,\" is also the end of its last sentence. Two of this author's characters are theorized to have run away either because they stole wine from the sacristy or because they were caught \"smugging.\" One of this author's characters devotes himself to Catholicism after hearing a sermon of Father (*) Arnall; in the first episode of another novel, that character sits atop a Martello tower with Buck Mulligan. That novel by this author, which ends with the line \"Yes I said yes I will yes,\" depicts a single day in the life of Leopold Bloom. For 10 points, name this Irish author of Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man and Ulysses.", "answer": "James Joyce [the second line refers to Finnegan's Wake]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This thinker stated that the 18th century was the century of physical sciences, the 19th century was the century of biology, and the 20th century was the century of fear. An essay by this thinker in the collection Nuptials focuses on life during the namesake season and how even those in poverty can feel fullied. Another essay by this thinker proclaims that the only true serious philosophical question is (*) suicide. A book by this thinker is the subject of a namesake explication by Jean-Paul Sartre. One book by this thinker starts with the protagonist's mother dying, and that protagonist later kills an Arab man. For 10 points, name this French absurdist philosopher of \"The Myth of Sisyphus\" and The Stranger.", "answer": "Albert Camus", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "category": "Philosophy"}, {"question": "Detecting these events using high-altitude balloons with microphones was the goal of Project Mogul. Aum Shinrikyo was accused of carrying out one of these events at Banjawarn Station in Australia. A satellite detected a double optic flash near the Prince Edward Islands that is suspected to be one of these events. New Caledonians and Algerians have demanded compensation from France for some of these events, such as (*) Gerboise Bleue. The Vela incident was suspected to be one of these events, while other ones took place at Semipalatinsk in the USSR. States that are not members of the Non-Proliferation Treaty, such as North Korea, still carry out these events. For 10 points, name these events, the first of which was at Trinity in New Mexico.", "answer": "nuclear tests [or nuclear explosions; or atomic bomb tests; or atomic bomb explosions; accept reasonable equivalents]", "subcategory": "Other History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "In The Technique of My Musical Language, a theorist from this country described seven modes of limited transposition. An orchestral work from this country includes a \"flower theme\" which is introduced by two clarinets and has a title derived from two Sanskrit words. One piano concerto by a composer from this country opens with a whip crack, while another was commissioned for the left-hand only by Paul (*) Wittgenstein. Movements like \"Crystal Liturgy\" and \"Abyss of the Birds\" are included in a quartet from this country. A piece from this country commissioned by Ida Rubenstein features a prominent snare drum ostinato; that piece is Bolero. For 10 points, name this country home to composers such as Olivier Messiaen and Maurice Ravel.", "answer": "France [accept French Republic or R\u00e9publique fran\u00e7aise]", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}], "bonuses": []}